<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Self Care</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="category">Category</string>
    <string name="category_image">Category image</string>

    <string name="journal">Journal</string>
    <string name="journal_entry">Journal Entry</string>
    <string name="date">Journal Date</string>
    <string name="new_journal">New Journal</string>
    <string name="hint_journal">Journal entry…</string>
    <string name="button_save">Save</string>
    <string name="journal_not_updated">Journal entry not updated.</string>
    <string name="journal_empty">Journal empty</string>
    <string name="clear_all_journals">Clear all journals</string>
    <string name="journal_saved">Journal entry saved</string>
    <string name="journal_updated">Journal entry updated</string>
    <string name="edit_journal">Edit Journal</string>
    <string name="delete_journal">Journal entry deleted</string>

    <string name="resources">Resources</string>

    <string name="meditation_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>What is Mindfulness Meditation?</h1>
        <p>Meditation is a form of enlightenment where one reaches a clear and pristine level of
        awareness. It\'s a journey to reach the destination of our working mind. This is where the
        practice of meditation and mindfulness meet at the crossroad. The focus is on the now. No
        longer are there worries about the past or the future. The path is the present moment.
        Mindfulness is a way of life where there are no distractions. There is no judgment. Having
        the ability to be self-aware of our surroundings. Through meditation, becoming mindful helps
        slow down every moment where they can be savored.</p>
        <p>There are many meditation practices but what makes meditation so great is that
        there isn\'t a perfect way to achieve its offerings. Whether young or old, meditation is
        a tool for anyone practicing self-care.</p>
        <h2>The Benefits of Meditation</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>Greatly increases mindfulness</li>
        <li>Lowers stress levels</li>
        <li>Controls anxiety</li>
        <li>Promotes emotional health</li>
        <li>Reduction of negative feelings</li>
        <li>Reduces implicit age & race bias</li>
        <li>Improves sleep</li>
        <li>Can decrease blood pressure</li>
        <li>Deeper relaxation</li>
        <li>Raises sustained attention</li>
        <li>Decreases feelings & symptoms of depression</li>
        <li>Enhances gratitude & self-awareness</li>
        <li>Boosts self-discovery</li>
        </ul>
        <p>There are other meditation techniques that exist that can help any particular domain of
        life. Mindfulness meditation is only the start. </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="journal_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Should you Start Journaling?</h1>
        <p>There is a reason that journaling has become so popular. Human beings like the essence of
        feeling productive. The achievement of checking something off the to-do list. Keeping a
        journal is much more than that. Journaling allows us to dump all of our current feelings
        and move on from them. It documents our current frequency. It documents our love. It
        documents our experiences. By documenting these things, an organization of thoughts is
        occurring. The mind is always thinking but at the end of the day, look back at all the good
        things that happened. Revisit those enjoyable and fantastic events. This is where journaling
        is unique for everyone.</p>
        <h2>Gratitude journal</h2>
        <p>Through the practice of gratitude, one\'s mind can grow into a million channels of happier
        states. By recalling what we are grateful for, this also builds upon mindfulness. It\'s an
        exercise for the mind to take in the present moment. What we have right now to be thankful
        for. This guides us through the path of appreciation and thankfulness. Certain situations
        can make this difficult but allotting the time to even jot a few things down each day or
        even once a week can bring us back to the correct frequency that we need to be on.</p>
        <h2>Bullet journal</h2>
        <p>Keeping a bullet journal allows for one to stay on track with daily routines, goals,
        events to participate in, etc. At the beginning of every month, plan and compile all the
        information into one central location. Have your goals, bills, special plans, dates,
        or lunch with a friend all included. That way each day can be truly focused upon.
        <br><br>Customization and creativity allow for a custom page here and there throughout the month.
        There might be a certain area of self-care that needs improving such as personal self-care.
        This could include exercising more, changing your diet, picking up a new hobby, getting
        proper sleep or just spending more "me time". Being able to write down these things
        helps remove worry and stress that can seem to pile up. </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="love_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Self love</h1>
        <p>Love is the basis of self-care. As we continue our daily lives, self-love is how we take
        care of ourselves. We must know how to love ourselves in many ways that are meaningful. Take
        action to really discover one\'s self. Do things that make you happy. Do things where you
        come first.</p>
        <p>Set aside some time to reward yourself no matter how small the success. We strive to
        better ourselves and become a better person. So when failure strikes, give yourself a break.
        Allow this as a time to grow and evolve. Look at gratitude to bring up your frequency and
        give your vibration a positive boost.</p>
        <h2>Major Actions</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>Mindfulness</li>
        <li>Spiritual Connection</li>
        <li>Good Feelings and Positive Emotion</li>
        <li>The Law of Attraction</li>
        <li>Love</li>
        </ul>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="music_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Music Soothes the Soul</h1>
        <p>Music is a part of every culture and there is good reasoning. Music instantly sways our
        emotions. This is because whenever we hear a song that we particularly like, the brain
        releases a chemical called dopamine which is often known as the feel-good hormone. There is
        the physiological rush of happiness or joy.</p>
        <p>Individual songs often serve as a bookmark for moments in our lives. They are tied to
        certain memories. Whether it was a song from your childhood or a new hit single that is
        topping the charts. These songs signify a sense of bonding. A bonding of current culture,
        styles, and unique decades.</p>
        <p>The benefits of music can range from improved mood to pain release. So whether we listen
        to our favorite music on our daily commute, singing a song at a karaoke bar, or appreciating
        a historical composer such as Ludwig van Beethoven, try to incorporate music into your daily
        self-care routine.
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="nature_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Mother Nature</h1>
        <p>In the time of concrete jungles, we are spending our time inside man-made structures. The
        importance of escaping the everyday world cannot be stressed enough. Reuniting with nature
        gives us the opportunity to&#8230
        <ul>
        <li>improve our mood</li>
        <li>gain clarity and mental energy</li>
        <li>reduce anxiety</li>
        <li>relieve stress</li>
        <li>realign of natural rhythm</li>
        <li>increase mindfulness</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Everyone doesn't live next to the prime nature spot but it doesn't have to be. Simply
        going for a walk, visiting a local park, or even caring for a garden can realign us with
        nature. We need the excuse to disconnect. So try to plan a weekend getaway here and there to
        get more greenery in your life. Whether a backpacking trip and camping aligns or visiting a
        lake to take in the scene, there are plenty of ways to take in mother nature.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="diet_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Self Love Diet</h1>
        <p>Putting your ego on a strict diet often results in catastrophe. A self-love diet is about
        eating mindfully. This is coming into portion control. Eat the amount that your body is
        physically hungry for. During this time, take in the flavors and be happy about what you\'re
        eating. When one is focused on self-love, a healthy nutritional diet will become a lot easier
        than forcing perfection and shame.</p>
        <p>Humans are creatures of emotion. The food that we eat often relate to how we are feeling.
        As we notice our feelings and the differences we feel when we eat a nourishing meal compared
        to an unhealthy one. There will be a greater urge to continue down the more nourishing path.
        We like to feel good so trust your body. If there is a craving for something, eat what
        satisfies the craving but look deeper afterward. There shouldn't be any judgment but how
        did eating that item makes your body feel? Make a note of how you feel afterward to help you
        decide about the next time you think about eating it.</p>
        <p>Dieting often falls into what is the latest and greatest fad diet. Often dieting is based
        on the results that we see on the outside and often forget about the internal changes.
        Follow routines and diets that make you feel alive. A diet that fills you with energy. Be
        internally aware and listen to your body. There are signs that we ignore because our goal is
        having the perfect body, or losing a bunch of weight. That goal can still exist but achieve
        it in a self-loving and healthy way. Move at your own pace but there should always be an
        effort to pamper our temple that holds our soul.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="travel_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Escape Your Comfort Zone</h1>
        <p>There is something magical about traveling. The magic comes when you leave familiarity
        behind and take the opportunity to discover what else is out there. Stagnation often makes
        our lives fly by in a blink of an eye but it doesn\'t have to be that way.</p>
        <p>Traveling allows us to reconnect with ourselves. Having the time to escape our daily
        routines and differentiate your self-care practices. Take a different path of fulfillment. At
        the end of a current adventure, take with you all of the things that you have discovered.
        Share your experience with others to keep these feelings fresh. Look back and be grateful
        that we live in such a beautiful world with fantastic people to share it with.</p>
        <p>Do the things that you love. Everyone is unique in their own way and people have
        different self-love and self-care techniques. In a social media crazed world, we can't help
        but to compare ourselves with others but living the life that you deserve is priority number
        one. Traveling has its own definition based on the individual. Whether that includes
        international travel, state or providence travel. Plan an adventure that is pioneered around
        what you love.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="crystals_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Healing Crystals</h1>
        <p>These stones are filled with energy which is one of the sole reasons that life even exists.
        This is because they come directly from our planet. Our
        planet that encompasses energy that is neither created nor destroyed. Each crystal has its
        own properties and healing properties. It is as simple as carrying a small one around on
        your person, keep them in your living space, hold them while you meditate, etc. The only
        right way is the way that works the best for you.</p>
        <h2>Self Love Crystals</h2>
        <ol>
        <li>Amethyst</li>
        <p>Is known as the Clarity Stone, Traveler\'s Stone, and the All-Purpose Stone". It resonates
        with the Crown Chakra and Third Eye Chakra. It is often placed in between the brows whenever
        there is a desire a boost in consciousness and vision.</p>
        <li>Aventurine</li>
        <p>Is known as the Luck Stone and Crystal of Opportunity. It resonates with the Heart Chakra.
        Choose this crystal whenever you need an increase in confidence or currently experiencing
        emotional issues.</p>
        <li>Black Tourmaline</li>
        <p>Is known as the Protective Stone and Remover of Obstacles. It is often used to absorb
        negativity and transmits positive energy. It is a wonderful stone to keep around the house
        or to be worn as a necklace. It also helps elevate consciousness so it often is used to help
        manifest one\'s desires.</p>
        <li>Citrine</li>
        <p>Is known as the Merchant's Stone. It resonates with the Solar Plexus Chakra so it can be
        used for aura protection. This crystal is selected whenever there is an invitation for more
        abundance and opportunities in one\'s life. </p>
        <li>Carnelian</li>
        <p>Is known as the Pleasure Stone and Confidence Stone. It resonates with the Sacral Chakra
        so it can be used to boost pleasure in one\'s life but also is an energy booster.</p>
        <li>Clear Quartz</li>
        <p>Is known as the Master Healer. It resonates with the higher chakras so it can boost
        consciousness, love, and self-awareness.</p>
        <li>Rose Quartz</li>
        <p>Is known as the Love Stone and Crystal of Love. It resonates with the Heart Chakra. So
        choose this stone when you need a boost of receiving and giving love because it emits
        vibrations of love and compassion.</p>
        </ol>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="oils_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Essential Oils</h1>
        <p>Essential oils are a must to boost your self-care. These oils are nothing more than
        plant extracts and are closely related to aromatherapy. Typically they are used with an oil
        diffuser but can be used in your bath or shower, skin care and cleaning products, and even
        replacing the air freshener with an oil spray that can refresh a room.</p>
        <h2>Special Self Care Needs</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>Sleep - chamomile, lavender, marjoram, sandalwood, and vetiver</li>
        <li>Mental Clarity - basil, clary sage, juniper berry, lemon and rosemary</li>
        <li>Stress Relief - clary sage, eucalyptus, peppermint, and tea tree</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Once again another area of self-care is focusing on nature and bringing it into our
        space. There are many more needs that essential oils can aid with. A lot of the benefits
        compound on one another so keep that in mind when you're picking your oils.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="chakras_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>Balanced Chakras</h1>
        <ol>
        <li>1st or Root Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to our feeling of being grounded, our foundation, and basic needs.</p>
        <li>2nd or Sacral Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to our connections with others, relationships, and accepting new events.</p>
        <li>3rd or Solar Plexus Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to self. This includes self-acceptance, self-connection, self-advocacy, and
        self-confidence.</p>
        <li>4th or Heart Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to love, joy, gratitude, and the ability to love one\'s self and others.</p>
        <li>5th or Throat Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to communication, self-expression, honesty, and active listening.</p>
        <li>6th or Third Eye Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to clarity, vision, balance, and the truth.</p>
        <li>7th or Crown Chakra</li>
        <p>Is related to one's consciousness and the connection with the Divine Source. Mindfulness
        at the forefront.</p>
        </ol>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="resources_data">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>More Resources</h1>
        <p>This application is just the beginning. It was made to introduce key self care ideas to
        individuals that have the desire to unlock your full potential and getting what we deserve
        out of our lives. Below are included links to explore deeper into certain areas. I have no
        affiliation with any of these individuals or companies. This journey is unique to all of us
        so these resources are just some of the places that I have benefited from personally.</p>
        <h2>Blogs & Websites</h2>
        <ul>
        <li><a href="http://www.morningcoffeewithdee.com/"><font color="7F7F7F">Morning Coffee With Dee</font></a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.mindbodygreen.com/"><font color="7F7F7F">mindbodygreen ran by Jasin and Colleen
        </font></a></li>
        </ul>
        <h2>Podcasts</h2>
        <ul>
        <li><a href="https://positivehead.com/spread-the-positivity/category/podcasts/"><font color="7F7F7F">The
        Positive Head Podcast hosted by Brandon Beachum</font></a></li>
        </ul>
        <h2>Books</h2>
        <p>The following books all have audiobooks available.
        <ul>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Secret-Rhonda-Byrne/dp/1582701709/"><font color="7F7F7F">The Secret by
        Rhonda Byrne</font></a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Power-Secret-Rhonda-Byrne/dp/1439181780/"><font color="7F7F7F">The Power by
        Rhonda Byrne</font></a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Power-Now-Guide-Spiritual-Enlightenment/dp/1577314808"><font color="7F7F7F">
        The Power of Now: A Guide to Spiritual Enlightenment by Eckhart Tolle</font></a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-Earth-Awakening-Purpose-Selection/dp/0452289963"><font color="7F7F7F">
        A New Earth by Eckhart Tolle</font></a></a></li>
        </ul>
        ]]>
    </string>

</resources>
